Guide to photograph album Photographs of Iran, Iraq, Caucasus and Turkey - A.P.H. Hotz AD.MC.061
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
A Collection of Photographs taken in Persia, Turkey and in the Caucasus, during a seven months' journey in 1891 (selection)
1890-1891
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus)
Thomson, John
Quaritch, Bernard
AD.MC.061
64 Photographic Prints 64 platinotypes (platinum prints) in 1 oblong album.
The album contains 68 captioned photographs of Albertus Paulus Hermanus Hotz's (A.P.H. Hotz) journey through Iraq, Persia (Iran), the Caucasus and Constantinople (Istanbul) with an accompanying index over 2 pages (ref5 and ref6). The photographs cover a broad topical scope and include group portraits, archaeological sites, architecture (including caravanserai, palaces and mausoleums) and landscapes. They begin in Bushehr and end in Istanbul.
Box 061
Biographical / Historical
Albert Hotz was born on 22 February 1855 in Rotterdam and came from a Dutch family of industrialists. His father, J.C.P. Hotz, was co-owner of a large iron-casting plant in The Hague. In 1874 he founded the Persian Trading Association (Vennootschap Perzische Handelsvereeniging J.C.P. Hotz and Zoon). His son, Albert Hotz, was sent by him to Persia to develop commercial activities. In 1873 Nasser ed-din Shah visited Europe for the first time. The news surrounding his visit placed Persia on the minds of businessmen keen to explore new markets. Following this visit, the Dutch consul-general in Boushehr (Bushehr), Mr. Keun van Hoogerwoerd, was convinced of good trading possibilities and promoted Dutch business activities in Persia.
Albert Hotz was interested in all forms of Persian trade. He undertook business activities in several fields. Next to his interest for different trade products, such as tapestry and opium, he was the first who drilled for oil in Daliki (Dalaki) in Khuzestan Province. He was also interested in exploiting coal mines and was involved in establishing the Imperial Bank of Persia. Hotz also sought for irrigation possibilities in some parts of Persia and the development of the Karun river. As of 1890 Hotz owned different trade offices in Basra, Bousher, Shiraz, Soltanabad and Esfahan. In 1890-1891 Hotz undertook a journey through Persia, the Caucasus and Russia for pleasure, also visiting his trade offices en route. During this journey he took and bought over 2,700 photographs of all those products, and possible trade and business-activities. The photographs (platinum prints) he took were developed by the then well-known English photographer John Thomson (1837-1921). Hotz placed them in several photo albums. Some albums served as public relation material. They contain photographs selected on special themes and have titles such as 'Tapestry', 'Road-making' or 'The personnel of J.C.P. Hotz and Co. in Persia'. These albums, which contain the more 'realistic and objective' images of Persia, were donated to institutions and business partners to persuade them of the good trade and business opportunities in Persia. Hotz's interest in Persia did go further than trade and business. He had a keen interest in the history and culture of Persia. Next to photographs, he collected a large number of books, atlases, geographical works and all kinds of documentation on Persia.
In 1893 he married Lucy Helen Woods, daughter of Henry Woods, Pasha, a British naval officer who worked as an aide-de-camp for Sultan Abdulhamid II (1876-1909) in Istanbul. They had three children.
In 1903 his commercial activities in Persia ended, but he remained very interested in everything that happened there. In 1906 he became a member of the Commissie van Advies voor 's Rijks Geschiedständige Publicatiën in The Hague and he wrote about the role of the Verenigde Oostindische Compagnie in Persia. 1909-16 he worked at the Dutch consulate in Beirut, in 1917 he became consul and on April 21, 1921 he retired. In poor health he went to Lugano in Switzerland to be close to his son Hendrik, who was ill in the Davos sanatorium. He died the same year (1930) on 11 April in Cologny. Hotz was buried in the Rotterdam suburb of Crooswijk. In 1935, his widow, Lucy Helen Woods, donated most of Hotz's materials to Leiden University.
Edited excerpts from: Corien J.M. Achour-Vuurman, Carmen Pérez González, Reza Sheikh (2008) 'Eyes on Persia. Late Nineteenth-Century Persia in the Hotz Photographic Collection' Exhibition Leiden University Library. https://socrates.leidenuniv.nl/view/item/1843487/datastream/PDFA/download and Wikipedia
Page "Albertus Paulus Hermanus Hotz". In: Wikipedia – The free encyclopedia. Edit status: March 12, 2022, 23:30 UTC. URL: https://de.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Albertus_Paulus_Hermanus_Hotz&oldid=221048358 (Accessed: March 13, 2023, 10:01 UTC)
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received.
Conditions Governing Access
Repository permission is required for access. Please contact Akkasah Photography Archive, akkasah@nyu.edu +971 2628 5531
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Bernard Quaritch Ltd 11th January 2018. Prior provenance unknown.
Existence and Location of Copies
Bibliothèque de l'Institut National d'Histoire de l'Art, collections Jacques Doucet https://bibliotheque-numerique.inha.fr/collection/?refine[Creator][]=Thomson%2C+John+%281837-1931%29%24%24%24Photographe
Existence and Location of Originals
https://www.bibliotheek.universiteitleiden.nl/
Scope and Contents
The album contains 68 captioned photographs of Albertus Paulus Hermanus Hotz's (A.P.H. Hotz) journey through Iraq, Persia (Iran), the Caucasus and Constantinople (Istanbul) with an accompanying index over 2 pages (ref5 and ref6). The photographs are a selection from the ten albums (over 2,700 photographs) taken and purchased by Hotz during his travels. The topics of the photographs cover a broad scope and include group portraits, archaeological sites, architecture (including caravanserai, palaces and mausoleums) and landscapes. There are notable portraits of Hajee Sayid Ibrahim, Turkish Consul in Shiraz and H.R.H. Masoud Mirza Zel-es-Sultan, the eldest son of the Shah and the governor of Isfahan. The photographs begin in Bushehr and feature Khark Island, Basra, Baghdad, Mohamrah,Bender-i-Nasiri, Ahvaz, Shushtar,Dalaki, Kazerun, Shiraz, Persepolis, Isfahan, Sultanabad, Ibrahimabad, Tehran, Tabriz, Yerevan, Tbilisi, Vladikavkaz and Istanbul.
Bibliography
Pérez González, C., Aesthetical approach to the Hotz Photo Collection. Portraits. [S.l.], 2008. Vuurman, C. and Th. Martens, Perzië en Hotz. Beelden uit de fotocollectie-Hotz in de Leidse Universiteitsbibliotheek. Leiden 1995. (Kleine publicaties van de Leidse Universiteitsbibliotheek, 19).
Corien J. M. Vuurman (2013) 'Greetings from Shiraz, the city of the purest air and clearest sky in the world': Ordinary Pictorial Delights from the Collections of Leiden University Library, History of Photography, 37:1, 32-47, DOI: 10.1080/03087298.2012.728023
Corien J.M. Achour-Vuurman, Carmen Pérez González, Reza Sheikh (2008) 'Eyes on Persia. Late Nineteenth-Century Persia in the Hotz Photographic Collection' Exhibition Leiden University Library, 2008. https://socrates.leidenuniv.nl/view/item/1843487/datastream/PDFA/download
Page "Albertus Paulus Hermanus Hotz". In: Wikipedia – The free encyclopedia. Edit status: March 12, 2022, 23:30 UTC. URL: https://de.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Albertus_Paulus_Hermanus_Hotz&oldid=221048358
Photographic Prints; Iran; Iraq; Caucasus; Constantinople; Trade; Tbilisi, Georgia; Yerevan (Armenia); Quaritch, Bernard
- The front cover of the album 'Photographs of Iran, Iraq, Caucasus, and Turkey.', 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref1; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Iran; Iraq; Yerevan (Armenia); Tbilisi, Georgia; Istanbul, Turkey
- The inside front cover of the album 'Photographs of Iran, Iraq, Caucasus, and Turkey.', 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref2; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Iran; Iraq; Istanbul, Turkey; Yerevan (Armenia); Tbilisi, Georgia
- A blank page in the album 'Photographs of Iran, Iraq, Caucasus, and Turkey.', 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref3; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Iran; Iraq; Yerevan (Armenia); Istanbul, Turkey; Tbilisi, Georgia
- A blank page in the album 'Photographs of Iran, Iraq, Caucasus, and Turkey.', 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref4; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
- The first page of the album's index., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref5; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Iran; Iraq; Yerevan (Armenia); Tbilisi, Georgia; Istanbul, Turkey; English Writing
- The second page of the album's index., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref6; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  English Writing; Iran; Iraq; Istanbul, Turkey; Yerevan (Armenia); Tbilisi, Georgia
- A view of boats docked in Bushire (Bushehr), Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref7; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Iran; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Men; Crowds; Coast; English Writing; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Regional/National Dress; Arabian/Persian Gulf
- A view of the British Residency in Bushire (Bushehr), Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref8; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iran; English Writing; Buildings; Architecture
- The facade of the Imperial Bank of Persia taken from the street in Bushire (Bushehr), Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref9; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iran; Streets/Roads; English Writing; Men; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Buildings; Architecture; Banks; Offices; Head Covers/Veils
- A view of the road to Sebzabad (Sabz Abad) taken in Bushire (Bushehr), Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref10; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Streets/Roads; Iran; Palm Trees; English Writing
- An 'imaret' house (charity house) outside Bushire (Bushehr), Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref11; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Charity; Buildings; Architecture; Iran
- Remains of a Dutch fortress and a ships on the coast in Kark (Kharg Island), Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref12; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iran; Coast; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Arabian/Persian Gulf; English Writing; Forts/Castles; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- A view of the Shatt al-Arab, a river in Bassorah (Basra), Iraq. A turkish man-of-war sits in the river next to the Turkish commodore's house., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref13; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Basra, Iraq; Buildings; Architecture; Boats/Ships; Water; Transportation; Palm Trees; Rivers; Officials
- A view of the creek in Bassorah (Basra) that leads to Menawee, a settlement on the Shatt al-Arab, 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref14; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Basra, Iraq; Water; Rivers; Palm Trees; Buildings; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Men; Women; English Writing
- A view of a creek taken halfway between Basra and the Shatt al-Arab., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref15; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Palm Trees; Men; Regional/National Dress; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Basra, Iraq; English Writing; Buildings; Rivers; Water
- A portrait of three men on the terrace of a house in Baghdad, Iraq., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref16; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Baghdad, Iraq; Buildings; Men; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Architecture; English Writing; Houses
- A group portrait of several men, women, and children in Moammareh (Mohmrah)., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref17; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iraq; Men; Boys; Children; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Palm Trees; Moammareh, Minushahr, Khuzestan Province, Iran
- A view of the governor's house adjacent to a European firm in Bender-i-Nasiri., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref18; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tents; Buildings; Officials; Flags; Landscapes; Iran; English Writing
- A group portrait of several men and children (Sheikh Mizal Khan's men) in Ahvaz, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref19; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Men; Children; Boys; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Canes/Walking Sticks; Guns; Weapons; Girls; Jewelry
- A view of the Karun River where the Shateit, the Dig, and the Gergar at Bend-i-Ker come together., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref20; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iran; Rivers; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Flags; Landscapes; English Writing
- A view of Shushtar Iran, including the the 'Bourge,' taken from a gateway leading to the Valerianus Bridge., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref21; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Bridges; Architecture; Buildings; Iran; Mountains/Hills; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- The Valerianus Bridge, standing over the Gergar River, in Shushtar, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref22; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Bridges; Architecture; Iran; Rivers; Water; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Dams/Barrages; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; English Writing
- A petroleum camp in Dalaki, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref23; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tents; Petroleum industry and trade.; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Iran; English Writing
- A pack of animals in the mountains on the way from Bushire (Bushehr) to Shiraz, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref24; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iran; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Camels; Horses; Animals; Men; Group Portraits; Outdoors; Shiraz, Fars Province, Iran
- A view of a vineyard in Kazerun, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref25; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Men; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Parks; Gardens; Forest/Woodlands; Agriculture/Farms
- A view of a line of camels on the way from Bushire (Bushehr) to Shiraz, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref26; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Shiraz, Fars Province, Iran; Iran; English Writing; Camels; Animals; Streets/Roads; Mountains/Hills
- A view of Shiraz, Iran, taken from Tjah Kaleh-i Bender., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref27; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Agriculture/Farms; Buildings; Landscapes; Shiraz, Fars Province, Iran; Iran; Gardens; Parks
- A group of men in the courtyard of a merchant's house in Shiraz, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref28; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Shiraz, Fars Province, Iran; Men; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Houses; Buildings; Architecture; Gardens
- A portrait of Hajee Seyid Ibrahim, the Turkish consul, and another man., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref29; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Shiraz, Fars Province, Iran; Officials; Fez/Tarboush; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Men; Group Portraits; Jewelry; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Architecture
- A view of Bagh dil Gusha (Garden of Heart's Delights), owned by Sahib Diwan in Shiraz, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref30; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Shiraz, Fars Province, Iran; English Writing; Boys; Men; Children; Group Portraits; Landscapes; Parks; Gardens; Fez/Tarboush; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Architecture
- A view of the Hafizieh Cemetery, which contains the Tomb of Hafez, in Shiraz, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref31; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Shiraz, Fars Province, Iran; Cemeteries; Tents; Tombs/Mausoleums; Architecture; Men; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Gardens; Parks; Poetry; Monuments/Memorials
- A view of the Tomb of Hafez in Shiraz, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref32; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Poetry; Tombs/Mausoleums; Monuments/Memorials; Tents; English Writing; Cemeteries; Gardens; Parks; Shiraz, Fars Province, Iran
- Tahkt-i-Kavam (Qavam). Mausoleum of a former governor of Shiraz in the Hafizieh Cemetery., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref33; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Shiraz, Fars Province, Iran; English Writing; Books; Men; Regional/National Dress; Buildings; Architecture; Monuments/Memorials; Cemeteries; Tombs/Mausoleums; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Gardens; Parks; Officials
- A caravanserai in Shiraz., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref34; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Shiraz, Fars Province, Iran; English Writing; Camels; Animals; Buildings; Hotels; Architecture; Men; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress
- A general view of Persepolis taken from the north side and the north platform in Persepolis, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref35; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iran; English Writing; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Mountains/Hills
- Inscriptions of travellers' names on the Porch of Xerxes, Persepolis, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref36; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Signatures
- A general view of Persepolis, Iran, taken from the east., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref37; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Mountains/Hills; Architecture; Landscapes
- A man next to the 'combat of king and monster' relief sculpture in the Palace of Darius, Persepolis, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref38; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Individual Portraits; Men; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Regional/National Dress; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Statues/Sculptures; Palaces; Buildings; Bags/Purses
- The Tomb of Cyrus in Persepolis, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref39; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Tombs/Mausoleums; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Mountains/Hills; Cemeteries
- A group of women weaving a rug near the Tomb of Cyrus in Persepolis, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref40; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Women; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Machines; Workers; Countryside/Rural; Mountains/Hills; Jewelry; Group Portraits; Bags/Purses; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Tombs/Mausoleums
- A view of the talar and gate to the Ali Qapu Palace in Isfahan, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref41; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Palaces; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Horses; Animals
- A portrait of H.R.H. Masoud Mirza Zel-es-Sultan, the eldest son of the Shah and the Governor of Isfahan., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref42; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; Officials; English Writing; Iran; Facial Hair; Men; Individual Portraits; Medals/Insignia; Animals; Swords/Knives; Weapons; Furnishings; Fez/Tarboush; Officials
- The Chaharbagh approach from the Si-o-se-pol (Allahverdi Khan Bridge), Isfahan, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref43; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Landscapes; Architecture; Buildings; Gardens; Parks; Bridges; Men
- The Sultan Hussein Mosque in the Chaharbagh, Isfahan, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref44; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iran; English Writing; Buildings; Architecture; Mosques; Religious Sites; Gardens; Parks; Water
- A group portrait of men and boys on Si-o-se-pol (Allahverdi Khan Bridge) in Isfahan, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref45; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Bridges; Architecture; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Men; Boys; Children; Fez/Tarboush; Head Covers/Veils; Dervishes
- A street in Jolfa, the Armenian quarter in Isfahan, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref46; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Streets/Roads; Architecture; Gardens; Parks; Buildings